<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: freelancing | siliconsenthil.in]]></title>
  <link href="http://siliconsenthil.in/blog/categories/freelancing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://siliconsenthil.in/"/>
  <updated>2015-11-05T07:11:28+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://siliconsenthil.in/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Senthil V S]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why freelancing]]></title>
    <link href="http://siliconsenthil.in/blog/2015/11/05/why-freelancing/"/>
    <updated>2015-11-05T06:11:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://siliconsenthil.in/blog/2015/11/05/why-freelancing</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Once I believed, freelancing is for people who could not find a stable job or lack coworking skills. But not anymore.</p>

<p>Over a period I'm observing a change. Slowly I feel I'm being caged in a typical company employment. There're compromises to make, to keep the 'formal' employment going. I have less freedom. And now, I'm looking to do freelancing.</p>

<p>But why?</p>

<!--more-->


<h3>Flexibility &amp; Work-life balance</h3>

<p>  It feels so relieving to think, that I'm not bounded by 40 hours. I decide my work-hours whether its 20 or 60. And, NO approvals for leave. Yaay!</p>

<p>  There are times when personal life demands more time and energy. It gets lot easier with freelancing. And obviously, sometimes I wanna do more. I can comfortably balance between these two.</p>

<h3>My passion</h3>

<p>I like certain kind of problems to solve. I'm comfortable in few technologies and I wanna master. With freelancing, I gotta 'choose' to follow my passion rather than being 'assigned' to do.</p>

<h3>Pay</h3>

<p>My company charges a way more to client than what it pays to me. Obviously there's a cost to infrastructure and culture. But, somewhere I feel I lost the ability to negotiate and make maximum out of my skills. Deciding my pay is my right. Isn't it?</p>

<p>And, freelancing pays more, typically.</p>

<h3>Home</h3>

<p> Daily, I do not have to travel just to work. Someone has to be physically present to work sounds so old. Isn't it? Given the tools and cheap high spead internet, working from home is very effective. You can save minimum on one hour everyday. And you burn less carbon. It's good for you, people on road and the environment.</p>

<h3>Stress</h3>

<p>After all, you're not working for deadlines someone else committed. I get to decide my timelines. No politics. No pushy meetings. After all, I gotta work for only the commitments I made. Sounds so straightforward.</p>

<p>When I decided to do freelancing, I went thro many sites and I felt lost. Some of them were very generic. The space looked like a busy/noisy market. But I wanted something elegant, genuine and exclusive. I wanted to be in a ecosystem that respects talent. I want to be amongst peers who are good at what they do.</p>

<p>One of my friends is doing freelancing and he introduced me to <a href="https://www.toptal.com">Toptal</a>. Having time spent and understanding it, I understood Toptal is not 'one-more-freelancing-site'. It really echoed my thought of standing amongst valuable peers which is ensured by their screening process.</p>

<p>I'm excited about it. Let's see how it goes. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
